# **Jack Neville**

Computer Programmer - Nottingham

+447341198432 jack@jackneville.com 30 years old www.jackneville.com

I have been playing professional rugby for the last 6 years in Hong Kong, Spain and now Nottingham. It has been a challenge to find the appropriate work/study endeavour to compliment my rugby commitments however over the last three years I have put my focus into computer programming. Primarily through self-study, and more recently through part time employment as a back-end programmer, I have become proficient in Python, REST APIs and numerous technology systems. Over the years, I also have secured ad-hoc freelance work in Data

analytics to speed up big data excel spreadsheets. Although I have experience in a number of skills I am looking for a role in backend programming or in data science as the end of my rugby

career is fast approaching.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### theDesk, Hong Kong — Back-end Programmer

July 2021 - July 2022

Co-working space company based in HK. I primarily worked remotely from Madrid where I was playing full-time rugby.

- Built python APIs to manage company contacts and addresses stored on MongoDB. Created dynamic GET endpoint requests as well as POST, PUT and DELETE request endpoints to manage the online database.
- Delivered a dynamic web-scraping script to collect HK, LinkedIn members information in different industries.

## **EY,** Hong Kong — Senior Associate in Business Development 2016 - 2017

Transitioned to a part time role within EY when started 1st full-time rugby contract.

- Upgraded the client feedback recording process following an engagement.
- Initiated calls with project leads in other locations to find best practice and communicate areas of improvement.

## **EY,** Hong Kong — Business Consultant in APAC Risk 2015 - 2016

- Awarded team leader on Source of Wealth Project within a large, multinational bank. This
  was due to a consistent high standard of files submitted and display of clear understanding
  of HKMA requirements.
- Achieved high end of year rating and was on course for promotion to Senior Consultant if continued a full-time role with EY.

#### **TECHNOLOGY & LANGUAGES**

Languages: Python, HTML, CSS

**Technologies**: Flask, Git, AWS (EC2, VPC, S3, Lambda functions), MongoDB

**Excel:** VLOOKUP, Pivot Tables, INDEX/MATCH functions as well as VBAs and Macros

Other: REST APIs, Data scraping, Natural Language Processing, Regular expression

#### **PROJECTS**

**Website:** Designed and created my own website

**Games:** Using python I created a Card pairs game as well as Asteroids & Pong

#### LANGUAGE

**Spanish: Proficient** - Continuing to build on what I learnt when living in Madrid

### **ONLINE COURSES & EDUCATION**

**An Introduction to Interactive Programming in Python (Part 2), RICE University - Online** 

2020

**An Introduction to Interactive Programming in Python, RICE University - Online** 2020

Introduction to AI & Programming, Tecky Academy - Hong Kong

**Learn Python 2,** Code Academy - Online

**Learn Python 1,** Code Academy - Online

Excellence in Excel, BIWS

2018

#### **EDUCATION**

**Cardiff University,** UK — *Business Economics* 2011 - 2014

Barnard Castle School, UK — 3 As at A level 2008 - 2010

#### **INTERESTS**

Causes - Solutions to climate change and planet protection strategies

**Sport** - Rugby, Acrobatics, Squash, Tennis, NFL (only as spectator), Skiing, Snowboarding, Surfing, Golf

**Books** - Started a book club in HK. Malcolm Gladwell, Michael Lewis and Ken Follett are some of my favourite authors

Movies - David Fincher and Wes Anderson films